THE CHARACTERS, ORGANIZATIONS AND EVENTS OF THIS DRAMA ARE FICTIONAL
이 드라마의 등장인물, 조직, 사건은 허구입니다.
TWO DAYS BEFORE
이틀 전
Hey,
여기요,
can your boss get him back up?
네 상사가 그 사람을 다시 일으켜 세워 줄 수 있겠니?
Yes, he feels better.
예, 기분이 좋아졌습니다.
It would be humiliating
굴욕적일 텐데
to become impotent over something like that, right?
그런 일로 무력해지다니, 그렇죠?
And.
그리고.
By the way,
그런데,
I saw a girl like that next to Jung Gicheul.
정기철 옆에 그런 여자를 봤어요 .
Do you know who she is?
그녀가 누구인지 아시나요?
When your gangs fought,
너희 갱단이 싸웠을 때,
there was supposed to be a girl there.
거기엔 여자가 있었을 텐데.
-Correct. -Who the hell is that?
-옳은. -대체 누구야?
Our men say
우리 남자들이 말하길
she is a police officer.
그녀는 경찰관입니다.
From the SMPA or something.
SMPA 등에서.
The SMPA?
SMPA?
Nonsense, you idiots.
말도 안 돼, 바보들아.
No really.
아니 정말.
SMPA. Kiss my ass.
SMPA. 내 엉덩이에 키스해.
Why should I come all this way?
내가 왜 이렇게까지 와야 하는 걸까?
You could have come to me.
당신은 나에게 올 수도 있었어요.
Hey.
여기요.
I'll keep it short.
짧게 말하겠습니다.
Could you check if this person is with the SMPA?
이 사람이 SMPA 소속인지 확인해 주시겠어요 ?
I know you.
나는 당신을 알고 있습니다.
She is the daughter of one.
그녀는 한 사람의 딸입니다.
From whom?
누구에게서?
What was the name of the former commissioner?
전 위원의 이름은 무엇입니까?
Yu Dukhoon?
유덕훈?
This is his daughter.
이 사람은 그의 딸이에요.
-Real? -Yes.
-진짜? -예.
A well-known police family.
유명한 경찰 가족.
Commissioner Yu's two sons,
유 위원의 두 아들,
his daughter, even the son-in-law. All police officers.
그의 딸, 심지어 사위까지. 모든 경찰관.
Son in law? Then she is married.
사위? 그런 다음 그녀는 결혼했습니다.
Or divorced?
아니면 이혼했나요?
In a police family? Never.
경찰 가족에서? 절대.
What do you say about that?
그것에 대해 뭐라고 말합니까?
A married policewoman and a gangster?
유부남 경찰 과 갱스터?
How?
어떻게?
Are you quite sure?
확실합니까?
No confusion? That is her?
혼란은 없나요? 그 사람이에요?
Look.
바라보다.
Do you want to live here?
여기서 살고 싶나요?
This will be our house.
이곳이 우리 집이 될 거예요.
Once this deal is completed,
이 거래가 완료되면,
I'll start over here.
여기서부터 시작하겠습니다.
Will you be there?
당신이있을 것입니다?
Gicheul.
기철.
Isn't it nice here?
여기 좋지 않나요?
Because of this deal...
이번 거래 때문에...
Does it still have to be there?
아직도 거기에 있어야 합니까?
I have to see it through.
나는 그것을 끝까지 보아야 한다.
Everything will be fine. No worries.
다 괜찮을거야. 걱정 마.
Junmo, can't you stop here?
준모야 여기서 그만하면 안 돼?
If you prevent trade...
거래 막으면..
If you just stop now,
이제 그만하면
then nothing will happen to us.
그러면 우리에게는 아무 일도 일어나지 않을 것입니다.
Who is “us”?
???us는 누구야????
Euijeong, is it...
의정아, 그렇지...?
... because of Jung Gicheul?
...정기철 때문에?
Junmo.
준모.
I can ...
저 할 수 있어요 ...
...don't stop here.
...여기서 멈추지 마세요.
I will close this case.
이 사건을 종결하겠습니다.
THE WORST OF EVIL
최악의 악
The number is correct.
번호가 정확합니다.
Let's finish it.
끝내자.
Hello. Did you find out anything?
안녕하세요. 뭔가 알아냈어?
-Yes. -The name again?
-예. - 이름이 또요?
Officer Park Junmo.
박준모 경관.
- Park Junmo. -Ja.
- 박준모. -자.
-POLICE CHIEF? -Yes.
-경찰서장? -예.
-Next time it's my turn. -What?
- 다음은 내 차례다. -무엇?
Thanks.
감사해요.
Who is this?
누구세요?
A clueless policeman,
아무것도 모르는 경찰,
whose wife cheats on him with a gangster.
그의 아내는 갱스터와 함께 그를 속였습니다.
"Park Junmo"?
'박준모'?
Jung Gicheul, you son of a bitch.
정기철, 이 개자식아.
I will have you at any cost
어떤 대가를 치르더라도 나는 당신을 가질 것입니다
put behind bars.
막대 뒤에 넣어.
You have the material.
당신은 자료를 가지고 있습니다.
Good. Stay close on their heels.
좋은. 그들의 뒤를 바짝 따라가세요 .
Well done.
잘하셨어요.
I quickly go to the toilet.
나는 빨리 화장실에 간다.
WC
화장실
We're leaving, sir.
저희는 떠나겠습니다.
Captain, the black limousine has been there the whole time.
선장님, 검은색 리무진이 계속 거기 있었어요.
Don't jump to conclusions.
성급하게 결론을 내리지 마십시오.
We arrest the suspects when they load the boat.
우리는 용의자들이 보트에 짐을 실을 때 체포합니다.
Yongdae, it's me.
용대야, 나야.
Hallo, Boss.
안녕하세요, 보스.
Find out if Chief Seo is in Gangnam.
서과장이 강남에 있는지 알아보세요.
Yes, boss.
예 보스.
Why are you taking this all personally?
왜 이 모든 것을 개인적으로 받아들이시나요 ?
Because it's dangerous.
왜냐면 위험하거든요.
That's why I have to do this.
그래서 내가 이 일을 해야 하는 것이다.
Plus, I started it.
게다가 시작했어요.
I saw it as the only way I could live my life
나는 그것이 내 인생을 살 수 있는 유일한 방법이라고 보았다
and could change that of my men .
그리고 내 부하들의 그것을 바꿀 수도 있습니다.
But you keep that a secret from them.
하지만 당신은 그들에게 그것을 비밀로 유지합니다.
If they knew drug money paid for their stores,
만약 그들이 가게에 지불된 마약 자금을 안다면,
they would feel guilty.
그들은 죄책감을 느낄 것입니다.
Seung Ho.
승호
At some point I started
어느 순간 나는 시작했다.
to recognize myself in you.
당신 안에서 나 자신을 인식하는 것.
You pursue your goals
당신은 당신의 목표를 추구
stubborn and unyielding.
완고하고 고집불통.
That's why I trust you with this.
그렇기 때문에 나는 당신을 신뢰합니다.
It will not be easy,
쉽지 않을 것이다,
but I wish you luck.
하지만 행운을 빌어요.
Ok, Sir.
알겠습니다.
But if it gets too dangerous,
하지만 너무 위험해지면
then you have to stop.
그럼 그만둬야 해.
By the way, where does the trading actually take place?
그런데 실제로 거래는 어디에서 이루어지나요?
Here.
여기.
Port Seven.
포트 세븐.
Is the dealer Japanese?
딜러가 일본인인가요?
A Korean-Japanese skipper.
재일교포 선장.
He speaks Korean fluently, you can talk to him directly.
그는 한국어를 유창하게 구사하므로 직접 대화할 수 있습니다.
He just got out.
그는 방금 나왔어요.
Is the car already at the entrance?
차가 이미 입구에 와 있나요?
I don't see anyone yet.
아직 아무도 보이지 않아요.
Shin, look at it.
신, 이것 좀 봐.
OK, sir. I'll drive over.
알겠습니다. 내가 운전해서 갈게.
Seung Ho.
승호
Wake up.
깨우다.
Kwon Seungho.
권승호.
Captain, I think we missed her.
선장님, 우리가 그 사람을 놓친 것 같아요 .
Crap.
쓰레기.
Captain.
선장.
A car exploded on the street near the harbor.
항구 근처 거리에서 자동차가 폭발했습니다 .
Exploded?
폭발했나요?
Check it out on site.
현장에서 확인해보세요.
Damned.
저주 받은.
Come on. Wake up.
어서 해봐요. 깨우다.
Boss.
사장.
What just happened?
방금 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
What about our fabric?
우리 직물은 어떻습니까?
He is gone.
그는 사라졌습니다.
Damned.
저주 받은.
What's going on here?
여기서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
Are you OK?
괜찮으세요?
Get on.
타다.
Kyungjin?
경진?
How did he know you were here?
당신이 여기 있다는 걸 그 사람이 어떻게 알았나요 ?
That must have been Jungbae.
분명 정배였을 거야.
Nobody knows this route,
이 길은 아무도 모르는데,
except him, you and me.
그 사람 빼고, 당신과 나.
That was 30 kilograms.
30킬로그램이었죠.
These bastards.
이 놈들.
I spare them and they betray me.
나는 그들을 살려주 지만 그들은 나를 배반한다.
-Let's go to the hospital. -No.
- 병원에 가자. -아니요.
Let's go to Seoul.
서울로 가자.
Seoul? Why?
서울? 왜?
We have to find the material first.
먼저 자료를 찾아야 합니다.
Go ahead, go ahead!
어서, 어서!
Back to Seoul.
서울로 돌아갑니다.
And gather the boys.
그리고 소년들을 모아라.
-What happened? -I was there.
-무슨 일이에요? -나는 거기에 있었다.
The exploded car was our target.
폭발한 차가 우리의 목표였습니다.
But there was no one inside.
하지만 안에는 아무도 없었습니다.
What should we do?
우리는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
We're retreating to Seoul for now.
우리는 지금 서울로 후퇴하고 있습니다.
Yes, Captain.
네, 캡틴.
What did he say?
그는 무엇을 말 했는가?
Back to Seoul.
서울로 돌아갑니다.
Damned!
저주 받은!
What the hell is going on?
도대체 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
Boss, are you okay?
사장님, 괜찮으세요?
Choi Jungbae and Oh Kyungjin betrayed us.
최정배와 오경진이 우리를 배신했어요.
- Byungwoo. -And, Sir?
- 병우. - 그리고 선생님?
What is Kyungjin up to today?
경진 씨는 오늘 뭐해요?
I don't know, sir. He disappeared without a trace.
모르겠어요. 그는 흔적도 없이 사라졌다.
Search every corner and find these motherfuckers.
모든 구석구석을 뒤져 이 개자식들을 찾아보세요.
Why are you standing there so stupid?
왜 그렇게 멍청하게 거기 서 있는 거야?
Come on! Move your asses!
어서 해봐요! 엉덩이를 움직여!
-Yes, sir! -Let's go.
-알겠습니다! -갑시다.
This is the list of dealers we know.
우리가 아는 딜러 목록입니다 .
We start grilling them immediately.
우리는 즉시 굽기 시작합니다.
Find out by any means possible whether they have recently
최근에 어떤 방법으로든 알아보세요.
had contact with Jungbae.
정배에게 연락이 왔다.
Yes, boss.
예 보스.
One day you realize
어느 날 당신은 깨닫습니다.
that you were blind.
당신이 장님이었다는 걸요.
All dealers from Gangnam Crystal.
강남크리스탈의 모든 대리점입니다.
Jung Gicheul has his people search all of Gangnam,
정기철은 사람들에게 강남 전역을 수색하게 하고,
so I think they will find Choi Jungbae soon.
그래서 곧 최정배를 찾을 것 같아요 .
When Choi and Oh were in our gang,
최씨와 오씨가 우리 갱단에 있었을 때,
Those were their phone numbers.
그게 그들의 전화번호였어요.
Check their call logs.
통화 기록을 확인하세요.
I made a risky decision and trusted you.
나는 위험한 결정을 내렸고 당신을 믿었습니다.
You disappoint me, Mr. Jung.
저를 실망시켰어요, 정 선생님.
This will cause great damage,
이로 인해 큰 피해가 발생하게 되며,
not only for me, but also for you.
나뿐만 아니라 당신을 위해서도요.
I am very sorry.
너무 미안 해요.
I will send it to you at any cost.
어떤 대가를 치르더라도 보내드리겠습니다.
I'll give you a week.
일주일의 시간을 드리겠습니다.
I can't wait any longer.
더 이상 기다릴 수 없습니다.
I understand.
이해합니다.
I will show no more mercy.
나는 더 이상 자비를 베풀지 않을 것이다.
What did he say?
그는 무엇을 말 했는가?
One week.
일주일.
We really need to find this stuff.
우리는 정말 이런 것들을 찾아야 해요.
Naturally.
당연히.
That was our lifelong dream. Of course we have to find it.
그것은 우리의 평생 꿈이었습니다. 물론 우리는 그것을 찾아야 합니다.
I'll go then.
그럼 내가 갈게.
However, Gicheul...
그런데 기철이...
... to be honest,
... 솔직히 말하자면,
I don't see any point in it. We already own all of Gangnam.
나는 그것에 아무런 의미가 없다고 생각합니다. 우리는 이미 강남을 모두 소유하고 있습니다.
I mean,
내 말은,
Every day there is new trouble and it becomes more and more dangerous.
매일 새로운 문제가 발생 하고 점점 더 위험해집니다.
The boys express their concerns.
소년들은 우려를 표한다.
Are you saying we should give up now?
이제 우리가 포기해야 한다는 말씀이신가요 ?
And?
그리고?
I'm just saying, we can sure...
내 말은, 우리가 확신할 수 있는 건...
Fuck it safe!
젠장 안전해!
Gut.
배짱.
I understand.
이해합니다.
POLICE OFFICE EUMSEONG DEPARTMENT FIGHTING CRIME
경찰서 음성경찰서 범죄수사과
Definition of province, what?
지방의 정의, 무엇?
Good afternoon, gentlemen police officers!
안녕하세요, 경찰관 여러분!
Oh, you're all alone.
아, 너 혼자구나.
Man, you need to clean this place up.
아저씨, 이곳을 청소해야 해요.
How can I help you?
어떻게 도와 드릴까요?
I am an investigator with Gangnam Police in Seoul.
저는 서울 강남경찰서 수사관입니다 .
Understand.
이해하다.
Is Detective Park Junmo here?
박준모 형사님 계세요?
I would like to visit him.
나는 그를 방문하고 싶습니다.
He is currently ill.
그는 현재 아프다.
Was?
였다?
Written in sick?
아픈데 썼어?
Is he very sick?
그 사람 많이 아픈가요?
No, I don't think it's that serious.
아니, 그렇게 심각한 일은 아닌 것 같아요.
What could be going on?
무슨 일이 일어날 수 있나요?
His wife certainly cooks well for him and everything.
그의 아내는 확실히 그와 모든 것을 위해 요리를 잘합니다.
I know trusting me was a hard decision.
나를 신뢰하는 것이 어려운 결정이라는 것을 알고 있습니다 .
And then my first trade goes wrong.
그리고 첫 번째 거래가 잘못되었습니다.
I apologize.
사과드립니다.
At least my judgment of character is confirmed.
적어도 나의 성격 판단은 확인되었습니다.
You didn't run away
당신은 도망치지 않았어요
you told me everything honestly.
당신은 나에게 모든 것을 솔직하게 말했어요.
Producing the material again is easy,
재료를 다시 생산하는 것은 쉽고,
not finding a trustworthy person .
믿을 만한 사람을 찾지 못함.
Haeryun, I will do everything I can to find the material
해륜아, 자료는 최선을 다해 찾아볼게
and save this trade.
그리고 이 거래를 저장하세요.
Somehow I'm always in your debt.
어쨌든 나는 항상 당신에게 빚을지고 있습니다.
Then pay them.
그런 다음 지불하십시오.
I trust you.
나는 당신을 신뢰합니다.
I know you'll make everything okay.
나는 당신이 모든 것을 괜찮게 만들 것이라는 것을 알고 있습니다.
Seung Ho.
승호
How depressed you are.
당신은 얼마나 우울한가.
I like you because you are confident.
나는 당신 이 자신감이 있어서 당신을 좋아합니다.
Don't burden yourself with everything alone.
혼자서 모든 일을 부담하지 마세요.
Tell me if you need help.
도움이 필요하면 말해주세요.
Your worries are mine too.
당신의 걱정도 내 것입니다.
Your father in China must be very upset too.
중국에 계신 아버지 도 많이 속상하셨을 텐데요.
I'm just ...
난 그냥 해요 ...
...worried that I'm getting you in trouble.
...내가 당신을 곤경에 빠뜨릴까봐 걱정됩니다.
That concerns me.
그게 걱정이에요.
I do this because I want to.
나는 내가 원하기 때문에 이것을 한다.
So don't feel bad.
그러니 기분 나빠하지 마세요.
Thanks.
감사해요.
I like the smell of the water.
나는 물 냄새를 좋아한다.
I smelled that every morning.
아침마다 그 냄새가 났어요.
Did you live by a river?
강가에 살았나요?
Ja, am Yitong.
자, 이통이에요.
In Changchun. It's beautiful there.
창춘에서. 그곳은 아름답습니다.
Changchun?
창춘?
And.
그리고.
It's peaceful there.
그곳은 평화롭습니다.
Quieter than here.
여기보다 더 조용해요.
-Hello? -It's me.
-안녕하세요? -나야.
Hallo, Boss.
안녕하세요, 보스.
Something happened?
무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Is Haeryun objective about this boy, Kwon Seungho?
해륜은 이 소년, 권승호에 대해 객관적인가요 ?
This weak girl was bound to cause problems.
이 약한 소녀는 문제를 일으킬 수밖에 없었습니다.
She has to take responsibility.
그녀는 책임을 져야합니다.
Damned!
저주 받은!
Haeryun.
해륜.
Do you want to wait in China?
중국에서 기다리시겠습니까?
The situation in Korea doesn't seem very good.
한국의 상황은 그리 좋지 않은 것 같습니다.
When looking for the material,
자료를 찾아보면,
who knows what will happen.
무슨 일이 일어날지 누가 알겠습니까?
When it's clarified,
밝혀지면,
we go together.
우리는 함께 간다.
Let's drive.
운전하자.
Dohyung.
도형.
I now know where the Chinese are.
나는 이제 중국인들이 어디에 있는지 알고 있다.
Changchun, Jilin.
길림성 장춘.
From Korea we know of their base in Changchun
한국에서는 창춘에 본거지가 있다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
and questioned the local police about the Korean-Chinese gangs.
그리고 현지 경찰에 조선족 갱단에 대해 심문했다.
The gang is called Donghobang.
그 단체는 동호방이라고 불린다.
Your boss is Lee Oson.
당신의 상사는 이오손입니다.
Our Korean source has been confirmed
우리의 한국어 출처 가 확인되었습니다
his daughter is Lee Haeryun.
그의 딸은 이해련이다.
We leave for Changchun immediately.
우리는 즉시 창춘으로 출발합니다.
We locate their drug factory with the help of the police there
우리는 경찰의 도움을 받아 그곳의 마약 공장을 찾습니다.
and wait for Korea and Japan to give us the signal to arrest.
그리고 한국과 일본이 우리에게 체포 신호를 보내기를 기다리세요.
Understood?
이해했다?
Yes, sir!
알겠습니다!
Good. Listen again.
좋은. 다시 들어보세요.
OK. The Chinese are ready.
좋아요. 중국인은 준비되었습니다.
All thanks to Detective Park,
모두 박형사님께 감사드립니다.
who plays with Haeryun's heart.
해륜의 마음을 가지고 노는 사람.
Sir.
선생님.
Now let's find Choi Jungbae...
이제 최정배를 찾아보자...
No, let's make the entire investigation public now .
아니, 이제 전체 조사 내용을 공개하자.
You're joking, right?
농담하는 거죠?
Things are getting riskier for Detective Park.
박형사에게 상황은 점점 위험해지고 있다 .
Officer Yu is also worried.
유 과장도 걱정이다.
-And? -What do you mean by "and"?
-그리고? - "그리고"는 무슨 뜻인가요?
Captain!
선장!
We are nearly there.
우리는 거의 다 왔습니다.
Please keep the focus until it's over.
끝날 때까지 집중해주세요 .
-Sir. -I'm serious.
-선생님. -진심이에요.
And calm down Officer Yu.
그리고 유 경관님 진정하세요.
We cannot reveal the couple's private feelings
부부의 사적인 감정은 밝힐 수 없다
allow the investigation to be compromised.
조사가 손상되도록 허용합니다.
Welcome back, sir.
돌아온 것을 환영합니다.
Would you like me to drive you to the office, sir?
제가 당신을 사무실까지 데려다 드릴까요, 선생님?
I wonder why things keep happening.
왜 일이 계속 일어나는지 궁금합니다 .
Why does shit like this keep happening to us ?
왜 이런 일이 우리에게 계속 일어나는 걸까요 ?
Sir.
선생님.
The boss told me to do something first.
사장님이 나한테 먼저 뭐라도 하라고 하셨다.
Was?
였다?
The document is in the glove compartment.
문서는 글러브 박스에 있습니다.
Yongdae, drive me back to Gangnam Police.
용대씨, 나를 강남경찰서로 데려다주세요 .
Yes, sir.
알겠습니다.
SEOUL POLICE DEPARTMENT
서울경찰청
I was always with the SMPA,
나는 항상 SMPA와 함께 있었고,
just not the security department.
보안 부서가 아닙니다.
Something happened, right?
무슨 일이 있었나요?
Guys who used to work for Jung Gicheul stole the meth.
정기철 밑에서 일했던 남자들이 필로폰을 훔쳤어요.
Then the trade stopped?
그럼 거래가 중단됐나요?
How is Junmo?
준모는 잘 지내요?
Junmo is safe and well.
준모는 무사히 잘 지내고 있어요.
But why did these police officers want to find Junmo in Eumseong?
그런데 이 경찰들은 왜 음성에서 준모를 찾으려고 한 걸까요?
What do you mean by that?
그게 무슨 뜻 이니?
Detective Hwang Mingoo.
황민구 형사.
He was at Eumseong Police Station yesterday.
그는 어제 음성경찰서에 있었습니다.
Detective Hwang.
황 형사님.
I heard you're looking for me.
당신이 나를 찾고 있다고 들었습니다.
Who are you?
누구세요?
Park Junmo of Eumseong Police.
음성경찰서 박준모.
Understand. Detective Park Junmo.
이해하다. 박준모 형사.
I think I've seen that one before.
저거 본 적 있는 것 같은데 .
Wen?
웬?
Maybe not.
아마.
Was?
였다?
Oh Mann.
오 만.
Why did you want to see me?
왜 나를 보고 싶었나요?
I was told you were on leave due to illness,
질병으로 인해 휴가를 냈다고 들었습니다 .
but you seem healthy.
그런데 당신은 건강해 보여요.
Alongside,
나란히,
Inspector Yu Euijeong is your wife, right?
유의정 경위님 부인이시죠?
Yes. And?
예. 그리고?
Yu Euijeongs Ehemann, Park Junmo.
유의정의 에헤만, 박준모.
Why does he come and meet Hwang Mingoo here?
그는 왜 이곳에 황민구를 만나러 온 걸까?
Park Junmo?
박준모?
Is he the husband of our boss's girlfriend?
그 사람이 우리 상사 여자친구의 남편인가요 ?
Well, I don't even know where to start.
글쎄요, 어디서부터 시작해야 할지 모르겠어요 .
Did you know,
알고 계셨나요?
that your wife is cheating on you?
네 아내가 바람을 피우고 있다고?
Of course not.
당연히 아니지.
This handsome boy's name is Jung Gicheul.
이 잘생긴 소년의 이름은 정기철이다.
A gangster in Gangnam.
강남의 갱스터.
The lady next to him is your wife, right?
그 옆에 있는 여자가 당신 아내죠?
Yes. And?
예. 그리고?
What do you mean by saying, "Yes, and?"
"예, 그리고"라고 말하는 것은 무엇을 의미합니까 ?
This is strange.
이건 이상해.
Your wife is having a good time with another man.
당신의 아내는 다른 남자와 즐거운 시간을 보내고 있습니다 .
Doesn't that bother you?
그게 당신을 괴롭히지 않나요?
Stay out of our family matters
우리 가족 문제 에 관여하지 마세요
and take care of your own.
그리고 당신 자신을 돌보세요.
What? How can you say that?
무엇? 어떻게 그런 말을 할 수가있어?
I'm telling you this for your own good.
나는 당신의 이익을 위해 이것을 말하는 것입니다.
My family is my business.
내 가족은 내 사업입니다.
Was?
였다?
You still look quite young.
당신은 아직 꽤 어려보이네요.
Do you want to retire yet?
아직 은퇴하고 싶나요?
How can you talk to me like that?
어떻게 나한테 그런 식으로 얘기할 수 있어?
It makes me sick to see you playing detective.
당신이 탐정 놀이를 하는 모습을 보니 마음이 아프네요 .
I will go now.
이제 갈거야.
Exactly!
정확히!
I know it again! I saw him.
또 알았어! 나는 그를 보았다.
Wo?
워?
When I went to get the document for the boss,
사장님께 서류를 가지러 갔을 때 ,
that's when I saw him.
그때 내가 그를 봤어.
I am certain.
나는 확신한다.
I'm smart.
나는 똑똑해.
What the hell is going on here?
대체 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는거야?
We can't find this meth park on the list .
목록에서 이 메타파크를 찾을 수 없습니다.
If we don't fix this,
이 문제를 해결하지 않으면
we'll have big problems.
우리는 큰 문제에 직면하게 될 것입니다.
I called his pager.
나는 그의 호출기에 전화를 걸었습니다.
He will definitely contact us.
그는 분명히 우리에게 연락할 것입니다.
What? He contacts us?
무엇? 그 사람이 우리한테 연락해?
You piece of shit.
이 똥같은 놈아.
Come with me.
날 따라와.
Come with me, you son of a bitch.
나랑 같이 가자, 이 개자식아.
You go now and do what the fuck you have to do,
넌 이제 가서 씨발 네가 해야 할 일을 해라 ,
and bring me that bastard Meth Park.
그리고 그 놈의 Meth Park를 나에게 데려오세요.
-Go get him! -Seungho.
- 가서 그를 잡아라! -승호.
Can we talk for a moment?
잠시 얘기 좀 할 수 있을까요?
In such times
그런 시대에는
we have to keep a cool head.
머리를 식혀야 해요 .
The lost material was millions...
잃어버린 자료는 수백만 달러였습니다 ...
No, worth billions of won.
아니, 수십억 원의 가치가 있다.
That can destroy everything.
그것은 모든 것을 파괴할 수 있습니다.
We know this!
우리는 이것을 알고 있습니다!
Our boys are working their asses off to find him!
우리 아이들은 그를 찾기 위해 최선을 다하고 있습니다 !
Who did they find with their worked asses?
그들은 일한 엉덩이로 누구를 찾았습니까?
What did you just say?
너 방금 뭐라고 했어?
Enough.
충분한.
Say that again.
다시 말해보세요.
Moderate yourself. I'm Hong Heesung.
자신을 조절하세요. 저는 홍희성이에요.
Hong Heesung.
홍희성.
Check all our graduates,
우리 졸업생들을 모두 확인해보세요 .
whether anyone is in contact with Jungbae or Kyungjin.
정배나 경진이랑 연락하는 사람이 있든 없든 .
You asshole ...
이 멍청아...
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Go.
가다.
We will talk later.
나중에 이야기하겠습니다.
Boss, I met Haeryun a few days ago.
보스, 며칠 전에 해륜을 만났어요.
Because we lost all the material
자료를 다 잃어버렸기 때문에
and they didn't pay,
그리고 그들은 돈을 지불하지 않았습니다.
They seem to have problems.
그들은 문제가 있는 것 같습니다.
It's all gone.
다 사라졌어.
Was?
였다?
When we got the material,
재료를 받았을 때,
Choi Jungbae came to our office and took everything with him.
최정배가 우리 사무실에 와서 모든 것을 가지고 갔습니다.
Holy shit!
젠장!
Choi Jungbae, that damn bastard.
최정배, 이 빌어먹을 놈.
Boss, does he have family or relatives?
보스, 그 사람은 가족이나 친척이 있나요?
Shouldn't we take them on?
우리가 그들을 맡아야 하지 않나요?
and find out where he is?
그 사람이 어디 있는지 알아낼까요?
Seung Ho.
승호
Kwon Seungho.
권승호.
Stay behind the line.
줄 뒤에 서십시오.
You can go now.
이제 가셔도 됩니다.
Hallo?
어이?
What's up?
무슨 일이야?
Is it urgent?
긴급한 일인가요?
I said I'll call when it's all over.
다 끝나면 전화하겠다고 했어요 .
Dohyung told me everything.
도형이가 다 말해줬어.
Let's meet to talk.
만나서 얘기하자.
Hello. do you remember me?
안녕하세요. 나를 기억해요?
And.
그리고.
The captain of our crime unit wants to ask a few questions.
우리 범죄수사대 대장이 몇 가지 질문을 하고 싶어합니다.
He is here in person.
그는 직접 여기에 있습니다.
Do you have a moment?
잠시 시간 있으세요?
Oh, sure.
그렇지.
This direction, please.
이 방향으로 부탁드립니다.
It does not take long. Get on.
오래 걸리지 않습니다. 타다.
There he is.
저기 있어요.
These are the communication protocols of the people on your list.
이는 목록에 있는 사람들의 통신 프로토콜입니다 .
Jungbae and Kyungjin haven’t called the number yet.
정배와 경진은 아직 전화를 걸지 않았습니다.
Here is the address of Choi Jungbae's parents.
최정배 부모님 주소입니다 .
These bastards need to be in touch,
이 새끼들 연락 좀 해줘야지
to sell it.
그것을 팔기 위해.
Dohyoung, check the logs regularly.
도형아, 로그를 자주 확인해봐.
Aside from that,
그 외에도
You could have told me that on the phone.
전화로 그런 말을 했을 수도 있었을 텐데 .
You know we don't have time.
우리에겐 시간이 없다는 걸 알잖아요.
I have to go.
나는 가야 해요.
Junmo.
준모.
What did he say.
그는 무엇을 말 했는가.
Junmo, are you ok?
준모, 괜찮아?
Am I ok?
난 괜찮아?
Euijeong, you know
의정아, 알지?
what situation am I in or not?
나는 어떤 상황 에 처해 있는 걸까, 아닌가?
Do I look okay?
나 괜찮아 보여?
Say if it's too much. I help ...
너무 많으면 말하세요. 나는 도움이 ...
Help me with what?
무엇을 도와주세요?
What can you do about this investigation?
이 조사에 대해 무엇을 할 수 있나요 ?
Stop showing up and distracting me.
그만 나타나서 내 주의를 산만하게 하세요.
Just stay out of here,
그냥 여기서 나가세요.
if you really want to help.
정말로 돕고 싶다면.
Junmo...
준모...
He said he was a police officer.
그는 자신이 경찰이라고 말했습니다.
He had to exchange the documents.
그는 문서를 교환해야 했습니다.
Damned.
저주 받은.
Say it very clearly. Word by word.
아주 명확하게 말해보세요. 단어 단어별로.
He said he was a drug detective,
마약탐정이라고 하더군요.
so I did as he said.
그래서 나는 그 말대로 했습니다.
He said he needed help with his investigation.
그는 조사에 도움이 필요하다고 말했습니다.
A drug investigator?
마약 수사관?
Detection?
발각?
Park Junmo.
박준모.
Why have you changed so much?
왜 이렇게 변했나요?
You are a police officer. Pull yourself together.
당신은 경찰관입니다. 함께 자신을 당겨.
I know that myself!
나도 그걸 알아요!
That's why I'm doing this investigation.
그래서 제가 이 조사를 하는 거예요.
Ok?
좋아요?
Why have I changed so much?
나는 왜 이렇게 변한 걸까?
Who pushed me to this point?
나를 이 지경까지 몰아붙인 사람은 누구인가?
Who dragged not only me but also Euijeong into this?
나뿐만 아니라 의정까지 끌어들인 사람은 누구인가 ?
Who the fuck was that?
도대체 누구였어?
-Junmo, please. -Who has me mind
-준모 씨, 부탁해요. - 누가 내 마음을 알아요?
and cost someone else their life?
다른 사람의 생명을 희생시켰나요?
It was you and fucking Cho Changsik.
너와 빌어먹을 조창식 이었다 .
Hey.
여기요.
-Am I not right? -Junmo.
-내가 옳지 않은가? -준모.
You know it yourself.
당신은 그것을 스스로 알고 있습니다.
I know how much this bothers you.
나는 이것이 당신을 얼마나 괴롭히는 지 압니다.
But you have to stay strong now.
하지만 지금은 강해져야 합니다.
Junmo.
준모.
He's going through a lot right now.
그는 지금 많은 일을 겪고 있습니다.
Please understand.
이해해주세요.
Hello, this is Seok Dohyung.
안녕하세요 석도형입니다.
Hello, detective. Here is the hall of the police pensioners.
안녕하세요, 형사님. 여기 경찰 연금 수급자의 홀이 있습니다.
Hello. What is it about?
안녕하세요. 무엇에 관한 것입니까?
I should call you if the person comes back.
그 사람이 돌아오면 전화해야겠어요 .
He was back?
그가 돌아왔나요?
And.
그리고.
He asked me to show him the document and others again .
그는 나에게 그 문서와 다른 것들을 다시 보여달라고 요청했습니다.
But I wasn't sure.
그러나 나는 확신하지 못했습니다.
He'll be back tomorrow morning.
그는 내일 아침에 돌아올 것이다.
I'll come to you immediately.
즉시 찾아가겠습니다.
He's coming now.
그 사람이 지금 오고 있어요.
Something happened?
무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Gangnam Union has become active again.
강남노조가 다시 활동하게 되었습니다.
It's where private detective Cheon Jinpyung
사립탐정 천진평이 있는 곳
Junmo's identity was revealed,
준모의 정체가 공개됐다.
and Gangnam Union's people were back.
그리고 강남연합의 사람들이 돌아왔습니다.
I'm going there straight away.
나는 곧장 거기로 갈 예정이다.
Please keep an eye on Jung Gicheul.
정기철을 지켜봐주세요.
Dohyung.
도형.
Be careful.
조심하세요.
You too.
너도.
Excuse me, sir,
실례합니다,
Chief Seo?
서 실장님?
Shouldn't we report this to the boss?
이거 상사한테 보고하면 안되는거 아닌가요?
We can do that once we confirm it.
일단 확인하면 그렇게 할 수 있습니다 .
But is it okay to meet police officers so personally?
그런데 그렇게 개인적으로 경찰을 만나도 괜찮을까요 ?
What's up with them?
그들에게 무슨 일이 있는 걸까요?
Are they different?
그들은 다른가요?
No, sir.
아닙니다.
If you stab them, they die like us.
찌르면 우리처럼 죽는다.
Hey, Euijeong.
안녕, 의정.
-Hello. -Oh, hi.
-안녕하세요. -아, 안녕.
-You'll definitely pass this time. -Thanks.
- 이번에는 반드시 합격할 거예요. -감사해요.
-Good luck!
-행운을 빌어요!
My goodness, he must be working really hard.
맙소사, 그 사람 정말 열심히 일하고 있겠군요.
RELATIONSHIP SON: CHOI JUNGBAE
관계 아들 : 최정배
Hallo?
어이?
Hey, it's me.
이봐 나야.
Chief Seo, are you on your way?
서과장님, 지금 가시나요?
Where are they?
그들은 어디에 있나요?
We have a fucking emergency at the office.
사무실에 긴급상황이 생겼어요 .
Choi Jungbae, that bastard...
최정배 그 새끼..
Let's meet to talk.
만나서 얘기하자.
I have to catch a rat first.
먼저 쥐를 잡아야 해요.
Come here. And alone.
이리 오세요. 그리고 혼자.
Was?
였다?
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
Write that down.
그걸 적어보세요.
It is in 361-5, Nokbeon-dong, Eunpyeong-gu.
은평구 녹번동 361-5에 있습니다 .
Nokbeon dong? Where is that?
녹번동? 그게 어디야?
Hall of police pensioners.
경찰 연금 수급자 홀.
Come now.
지금와.
Fuck.
못쓰게 만들다.
Gicheul.
기철.
Do you remember how you said
네가 어떻게 말했는지 기억하니?
when someone visits Gangnam,
누군가 강남에 방문하면
that they had to come to one of your stores ?
그 사람들이 당신 가게 중 한 곳에 와야 했다고요 ?
Your dream has come true, right?
당신의 꿈이 이루어졌죠?
Couldn't you stop what you're doing now?
지금 하고 있는 일을 멈출 수는 없었나요 ?
It's too dangerous.
너무 위험해요.
Euijeong, my dream hasn't quite come true yet.
의정아, 내 꿈은 아직 제대로 이루어지지 않았다.
I said I would be the "Emperor of the Night",
나는 "밤의 황제"가 될 것이라고 말했고 ,
and that I would marry you.
그리고 내가 당신과 결혼하겠다고 했어요.
Man, that was really cheesy.
정말 촌스럽더군요.
You're right. I could stop now.
네가 옳아. 이제 그만해도 돼요.
But I'm so close to the goal now,
하지만 이제 목표에 너무 가까워졌네요.
it would be a shame to give up.
포기하는 것은 부끄러운 일입니다.
Do not worry.
걱정 하지마.
I'll take care of everything.
내가 다 처리할게.
One second.
일초.
-Hello? -They caught Choi Jungbae.
-안녕하세요? - 최정배를 잡았어요.
-What? Where? -Our boys will take him to the office.
-무엇? 어디? - 우리 아이들이 그를 사무실로 데려갈 거예요.
Okay, I'll be there soon.
알겠습니다. 곧 도착하겠습니다.
Sorry, Euijeong, I have to go.
미안 의정아 나 가봐야 해
What's up?
무슨 일이야?
I'll explain later. Sorry.
나중에 설명하겠습니다. 죄송합니다.
Crap.
쓰레기.
Detective Park Junmo.
박준모 형사.
Yu Euijeong's husband, right?
유의정 남편 맞죠?
Why are you following us like a rat?
왜 쥐처럼 우리를 따라오는 거죠 ?
Seo Jongryeol?
서종렬?
So you know me.
그래서 당신은 나를 알고 있습니다.
Hey.
여기요.
"Hightech-Industriebezirk."
"하이테크-인더스트리베지르크".
"New airport in Yeongjongdo."
"영종도 신공항."
"International Business and Residential District."
“국제 비즈니스 및 주거 지역.”
"Sports facilities."
"스포츠 시설."
"Entertainment and tourism complex."
"엔터테인먼트 및 관광 단지."
"Maritimer Tourismuskomplex."
"Maritimer Tourismuskomplex."
Sir.
선생님.
Where is Chief Seo?
서과장님은 어디 계시나요?
Hey, I found the cop,
안녕하세요, 경찰을 찾았어요
who followed us and had us in his sights.
우리를 따라오시며 우리를 그의 시야에 두셨느니라.
-I found him. -Who is this?
- 찾았어요. -누구세요?
The boss's girlfriend's husband.
사장 여자친구의 남편.
-Open up. -What?
- 열어보세요. -무엇?
Open the fucking door!
빌어먹을 문을 열어라!
What should I do?
어떻게 해야 하나요?
Until I call you,
내가 전화할 때까지,
-hide somewhere. -What?
-어딘가에 숨어. -무엇?
The guy in there is a cop, so hide!
거기 있는 사람은 경찰이니까 숨어요!
Crap.
쓰레기.
You motherfucker.
이 개자식아.
Damned.
저주 받은.
Hey.
여기요.
Chief, was ...
팀장님은...
What's going on here?
여기서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
Park Junmo.
박준모.
Boss's girlfriend's husband.
보스 여자친구의 남편.
You know him, right?
그 사람 알지?
You said you know Yu Euijeong.
유의정을 아신다고 하셨어요.
Then you also know your husband.
그럼 당신도 당신의 남편을 알잖아요.
Or not?
아니면?
Yes, I know him.
네, 저는 그 사람을 알아요.
But he's a police officer.
하지만 그 사람은 경찰이에요.
I thought Yu Euijeong and her husband
유의정과 그녀의 남편을 생각했어요
had a plan to catch us.
우리를 잡을 계획이 있었어 .
I thought that.
나는 그렇게 생각했다.
But there was more to this shit.
하지만 이 일에는 더 많은 일이 있었습니다 .
Seok Dohyung from the SMPA Drug Squad.
SMPA 마약수사대 석도형입니다 .
Why did he pretend to be Park Junmo?
왜 박준모인 척 한 걸까요?
Hey.
여기요.
You know something about it, right?
당신은 그것에 대해 뭔가를 알고 있지, 그렇지?
Well, maybe not.
글쎄요, 아닐 수도 있어요.
Then we can just ask him.
그렇다면 그에게 물어보면 됩니다.
He had this with him.
그는 이것을 가지고 있었습니다.
Because he's a police officer.
왜냐하면 그 사람은 경찰이거든요.
Wait, Chief.
잠깐만요, 국장님.
Damned.
저주 받은.
If we kill a police officer in the current situation,
지금 상황에서 경찰을 죽이면
Everything gets even more complicated.
모든 것이 더욱 복잡해집니다.
Let's find another way.
다른 방법을 찾아보자.
I'll make it easy.
쉽게 할게요.
They finish it.
그들은 그것을 끝낸다.
Listen, Kwon Seungho.
들어봐, 권승호.
I don't want to doubt you.
나는 당신을 의심하고 싶지 않습니다.
Was ...
였다 ...
Chief,
셰프,
Do you now have...
지금 가지고 계시나요...
... suspect me?
... 나를 의심하나요?
My gut feeling is one of us is in cahoots with the cops.
내 직감은 우리 중 한 명이 경찰과 공모하고 있다는 것입니다.
Let's see who's right.
누가 옳은지 봅시다.
Stab him.
그를 찔러라.
What the ...
무슨 ...
Stab him, you bastard!
찔러라, 이 새끼야!
Damned.
저주 받은.
Subtitles by: Ingo Krallmann
자막: Ingo Krallmann